97. American Football. Huge men sprint across the field like gazelles, then smash into each
other like trains. One man is alone, inside a clear space, while other men fight to protect
him. Just before he falls under the weight of other bodies, he throws a ball high into
the air. Thirty yards away, it is caught. A touchdown. The crowd goes wild. This is
American football. It's the most popular sport in the United States, but it's not well-known
elsewhere. Two teams of 11 men fight to move along a hundred-yard field. Each team defends
its goal at the ends of the field. The men try to move a ball. The ball can be thrown,
played, or kicked. A team scores six points for carrying or throwing the ball across the
other team's goal line, and three points for kicking the ball between the other team's
goal posts. American football, called football in the United States, evolved in the nineteenth
century from different types of rugby which is played in the United Kingdom. Rugby has
a similar ball and similar rules to football. While American football is still clearly related
to rugby, the two games are now very different. American football was already a popular high
school and college game before it was recognized as a professional sport in 1892. The first
football league was established in 1920. Two years later, it changed its name to the NFL
National Football League, which still exists today. After 1958, when a great championship
game was played, football's popularity grew. Now it is the most popular sport in the United States.
The championship, now called the Super Bowl, is watched by more Americans than any other
television event. The game, with its violence, strategy, and passion, is deeply rooted in
American culture.